motu.com 2019-06-19

# Privacy | MOTU.com

MOTU values your privacy. Below we explain the personal information we do (and don’t) collect from you and the steps we take to protect it, in accordance with the laws of the United States and the EU GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation).

FIRST: The only personal information we collect is information you provide to us.  
This information could include (for example) your name, a mailing address, email address, or phone number – it depends on what you’re asking MOTU to do for you. If you supply us with personal information on our website, you will only be contacted so that we can provide you with the information, products, or services you have requested. If you make a purchase, of course MOTU will collect (and hold) all the information mentioned above, plus such things as your credit card number and billing address. If you license our software (or a trial version), MOTU collects the name and email address you enter plus your Internet (IP) Address and a unique machine ID, to compare with later uses. Occasionally – if you allow us – we might send you extra information about MOTU and its products, that we believe you would find interesting.

SECOND: When you browse MOTU’s website, you do so without revealing your identity.  
MOTU’s website uses cookies and your Internet Address only to present you with the proper information, and to keep your responses separate from other people using the website. We also collect information about which pages people visit, so that we can update our website as necessary. MOTU does not disclose IP Address, Domain Name, nor even other aggregated information to others. We’ll hang onto this information to analyze it, and then throw it away. You can, if you wish, delete or disable cookies in your web browser. Most of MOTU’s web site will still work, but some parts may not. (Note: Our website is not directed at children, so MOTU does not knowingly collect or maintain any information from children under age 13.)

THIRD: When you do give your information to us, we are committed to protecting its confidentiality.  
MOTU limits access to the personal information collected to employees of MOTU and its affiliates who need the information to fulfill their business responsibilities to you, and to us. Our employees and consultants are under strict confidentiality requirements. We may have to use third-party service providers to process information on our behalf for the purposes outlined above (see a current list here), but vendors and other outside contractors we engage are subject to contractual or regulatory requirements safeguarding personal information. MOTU stores information in The United States of America, and we retain it as long as needed to provide you support and information for the products you license and the services you request.

BUT: Courts and law enforcement might override our policies.  
At times we may be required by law or litigation to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public safety, disclosure is necessary.

NOTE: MOTU’s web site may be linked to other web sites.  
MOTU often creates links to other web sites. Of course, MOTU is not responsible for the content or privacy practices employed by sites that are linked from or to our web site. As you visit pages and sites of different businesses, please be sure to review the privacy policies applicable to them.

FINALLY:   
A long-time MOTU employee serves as our company-wide privacy officer, with responsibility for administering and implementing our Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or comments about MOTU’s Privacy Policy, the principles and procedures behind it, or the data stored for and about you, please email them to customerservice@motu.com to the attention of Data Protection Officer, or put them in writing, to:

MOTU  
Attention: Data Protection Officer  
1280 Massachusetts Avenue  
Cambridge, MA 02138

(Per EU regulations, this is also the contact information for the “Data Controller” with respect to your personal information.) From time to time, Mark of the Unicorn, Inc. (referred to here as "MOTU", "we", or "us") may modify this Privacy Policy.
